莫妮卡？
Monica?
现在几点？
What time is it?
9点
Nine.
可是外面还很黑
But it's dark out.
那是因为你老睡到中午，傻瓜
That's because you always sleep till noon,silly.
9点就是这么黑
This is what nine looks like.
那我该梳洗一下
I guess I'll get washed up then.
准备看日出
Watch that sunrise.
我不想再偷偷摸摸了
I'm getting tired of always sneaking around.
我知道，我也是
Me too.
不然我们去外面渡周末 就没人打扰我们
What if we went away for the weekend? No interruptions.
还可以赤身裸体
We could be naked the entire time.
整个周末？那可是很长
All weekend? That's a whole lot of naked.
我可以说我去开会 你就说去参加厨师研讨
I'll say I have a conference and you can have a chef thing.
我一直想参加纽泽西的烹饪大会
I wanted to go to this culinary fair in Jersey!
不过你不是去那里开会
Okay. You know you're not,though.
走吧
-Let's go.
等等，乔伊怎么办？
-Okay. Wait.What about Joey?
本集播出：“不想当阿吉”
The One with the Kips
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
你们知道我这周末要干嘛吗？
Hey，guess what I'm doing this weekend！
去纽泽西参加烹饪大会
I'm going to a culinary fair in Jersey this weekend.
真怪，钱德刚才说要去那里开会
How weird! Chandler just said he's got a conference there.
真有意思
That's funny.
钱德应该可以去康涅狄格州或佛罗蒙特州开会
Seems like Chandler's conference could've been...in Connecticut or Vermont.
我又不能决定在哪里开会
I'm not in charge of where the conference is held.
难道你希望大家认为我造假？ 因为我可没说谎
Do you want people to think it's fake? It's a real conference.
瑞秋在吗？我要找她
-ls Rachel here?I gotta talk to her
她出去逛街了
-No,she's out shopping.
可恶
-Damn!
怎么了？ 我叫艾蜜莉来
-What's going on?-I told Emily to come.
所以我得赶快跟瑞秋说
And I just need to,you know,talk to Rachel about it.
等等
Wait a minute.
艾蜜莉来了之后 你真的就不见瑞秋了？
When Emily comes,you won't see Rachel anymore?
我现在只能专心想着 “我可以见我老婆”
I'm focusing on the "I get to see my wife" part...
不去想我快胃溃疡的事
...and not on the part that makes me do this.
你们再也不能共处一室？
So you'll never be in a room together?
这怎么可能？
How will that even work?
我也不知道
I have no idea. I mean....
但是我一定会想到办法
But I assure you,I will figure it out.
看起来实在不可能…
It doesn't seem like it'll work.
大家好 嗨
Hi,guys.
怎么了？
What's going on?
我们正要帮莫妮卡翻床垫
We're flipping Monica's mattress.
我认为应该先抬起来再翻过来
So I'm thinking,basically,we pick it up and then we flip it.
这方法比我的主意好
That's better than my way.
你们能顺便帮我翻吗
Hey guys,would you flip mine too?
哦，拜托！
Oh,man.
我妈妈来信了
Oh,look! A letter from my mom.
瑞秋，你知道艾蜜莉要来
So,Rach?You know how Emily's coming?
我知道啊
Oh,yeah. I know.
听得到吗？
Can you hear anything?
当然，刚刚有人说 “听得到吗？”
Yeah,somebody just said,"Can you hear anything?"
乔伊的大屁股
Hey,Joey's ass.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
记得上次他们吵架分手时 我们困在房里没东西可吃吗？
Remember when they fought and broke up...and we were stuck here all night with no food?
罗斯在婚礼上说出瑞秋名字后 我猜旧戏可能会重演
When Ross said "Rachel" at the wedding,I figured it'd happen again.
所以我在这里藏了这些东西
So I hid this in here.
有糖果，猜谜…
Candy bars,crossword puzzles....
还有疯狂猜谜，我要
Mad Libs! Mine!
好，“说出房里某人的名字”
-Okay,"Name of someone in room."
钱德
-Chandler.
拜托，正经一点
Come on,seriously.
还有什么？杂志、洋芋片
What do you got in here? Magazines,Doritos
保险套？
Condoms?
谁晓得会在这里待多久
You don't know how long we'll be in here.
搞不好我们还得负责 繁衍人类后代
We may have to repopulate the Earth.
戴保险套还想繁衍后代？
And condoms are the way to do that?
有个关键问题
Anyway,it all boils down to this.
上次我跟艾蜜莉通电话
-The last time I talked to Emily
天啊，我的狗死了
-Oh,my God! Our dog died!
什么？
-What?
天啊，拉普死了
-Oh,my God! LaPooh,our dog!
拉普还活着？
LaPooh's still alive?
对不起
Sorry.
我妈说它被冰淇淋车撞到
It says he was hit by an ice cream truck
还被拖了…19条街
and dragged for...nineteen blocks!
我的天啊
-Oh,my God.
我们听到你在哭，别哭了
-Sweetie,we heard you crying.Please don't cry.
是拉普
-It's LaPooh!
我知道现在是拉普的事情 以后会好的
I know,it's LaPooh right now but it'll get better.
不可思议，我们到了
I can't believe it! We're here!
枕头上还放巧克力 我最爱这套
Chocolates on the pillows! I love that!
那你应该跟乔伊住 到处都有巧克力糖
You should live with Joey. Rolos everywhere.
太好了，没人会来打扰我们
This is so great. No one's gonna bother us.
我们可以尽情缠绵
And we're gonna do it.
我要跟莫妮卡上床了
I'm gonna do it with Monica!
钱德
Chandler,
钱德，上床就上床，别穷嚷嚷
Chandler，stop yelling that you and I are gonna do it!
我马上回来。好
-I'll be right back. -Okay.
万岁，莫妮卡快来 电视正在转播警匪公路追逐战
Oh,yes!Get in here. There's a high-speed car chase on!
我们要换房间
We're switching rooms.
天啊，他们给了我们玻璃杯！
Oh,dear God! They gave us glasses!
杯子上有口红印
The glasses have lipstick on them.
如果连杯子都没换 谁晓得还有哪些东西没换
Who knows what else they didn't change?
饭店没换杯子你就要换房间？
You wanna switch rooms because they didn't switch the glasses?
我本来不想说 地毯也有点臭
I didn't wanna say anything,but the carpet smells too.
亲爱的，我只是希望 过个完美的周末
I want this weekend to be perfect.
换个房间好吗
We can change rooms,can't we?
好吧，要换快换 5号直升机刚跟丢了
Okay,but let's do it now. Chopper Five just lost its feed!
“中央咖啡馆”
算了
Forget it.
记得我上次有事告诉你吗？
You know how there was something I wanted to talk to you about?
对
Oh,yeah.
你知道我很希望跟艾蜜莉合好
I'm trying to work things out with Emily.
不过有件事…
Well,there's this...one thing.
我要说了
Here goes.
我答应她…
I made a promise that
什么？ 你流鼻血
-What? -Your nose is bleeding.
天啊，你在流血。-又来了
-Oh,God! -You're bleeding.Oh,not again.
我祖父过世时也一样
This happened when my grandfather died.
抱歉
Sorry.
好了，对不起 你刚要说什么？
Gross.Okay. So I'm sorry. What did you want to tell me?
抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
我见不到你了
I can't see you anymore.
我知道，真离谱 我也看不到你 好吧
I know,it's ridiculous. I can't see you,either. All right.
我得塞一些卫生纸到鼻子里
I'm just gonna go shove a bunch of tissues in my nose.
我边塞你边说好了
Hey,do you wanna tell me while I do that?
算了
I'm good.
你们可能会喜欢这间房 太好了
-I think you'll like this room more. -Okay,great.
听说他只剩下一半的汽油
They say he's only got half a tank left.
一半？那还可以跑很久呐
Half a tank? Still lots of high-speed chasing to do!
他一定是想去加拿大
I'll bet he's heading for Canada
每次都用同一招
They always do.
我们必须换房间
-We're switching rooms again.
什么？为什么？
-What? Why?
这间房是花园景观 我们订的是观海房
This has a garden view. We paid for an ocean view.
只剩一间观海房 可是你们不喜欢
Our last ocean-view room was unacceptable to you.
那间房的地毯有味道
-The carpet smelled.
大海的味道？
-Like ocean?
是脚臭味
No,like feet.
抱歉，我可以跟你谈一下吗？
Excuse me. Can I talk to you over here for just a second?
钱德 来了
Chandler！-Ya
这些小人想占我们便宜 我才没那么蠢
These clowns want to take us for a ride. I won't let them.
我们可不是呆头鹅
We're not a couple of suckers.
说得好，马格西（《兔八哥》里的角色）
I hear you,Mugsy.
这些房间都还好啊 请你赶快选定，让我看…
All these rooms are fine.Just pick one so I can watch the
让我跟你一起好好度假
Have a perfect,magical weekend together with you?
天啊，他差点撞上油罐车
Oh,man,he almost hit a gas truck.
你看不看“海滩游侠”？
Do you ever watch Baywatch?
我喜欢这间
-This one I like.
没了，结束了
-Nothing. Nothing. It's over. Damn it!
竟然没有延长时间
This is regularly scheduled programming!
我想看他们访问邻居
-I wanted to see them talk to his neighbors.
我就在这，你可以跟我聊天
-Well,I'm standing right here...you could talk to me.
你又不认识歹徒
You didn't know him.
可以关掉电视吗？
Can we turn the TV off?
难道整个周末都要看电视？
Do we really want to spend the weekend like this?
抱歉，我是不是 妨碍你换房间了？
Am I getting in the way of the room-switching fun?
你火大可别怪到我身上 否则该怪谁？
Don't blame me for tonight.Who should I blame?
那个拖着行李 跑了10间房的倒霉服务生？
The nice bellman who had to drag out luggage to 10 different rooms?
我不知道
I don't know
或许该怪那个以为用半箱汽油 可以从纽约跑到加拿大的家伙
how about the idiot who thought he could drive...from Albany to Canada on half a tank of gas?
不要说死者的坏话
Do not speak ill of the dead.
我们出来是为了过浪漫周末
We're supposed to be spending a romantic weekend together.
你到底哪里有毛病？
What's the matter?
我只是想看点电视 有何不对？
I just want to watch a little television.What is the big deal？
放轻松，妈
Jeez,relax,Mom.
你说什么？
What did you say?
我说，“放轻松，莫”
I said,"Jeez,relax,Mon."
你喜欢看高速逃亡？ 现在就看好了
You know what,Chandler? You like fast getaways? Watch this.
我不喜欢看高速逃亡 我要看的是飞车逃亡
I don't like fast getaways,I like car chases.
嗨
Hey.
瑞秋，我一直有话要告诉你
I've been wanting to tell you something
我非说不可
and I just have to get it out.
什么事？
Okay. What's up?
在我说话之前，你确定 不会再流鼻血？
Okay,before I tell you I just have to know...is your nose okay?
你家其他的宠物都很健康？
Are all the other family pets in good health?
大卫还在伤心拉普过世
Well,Davey's still pining after LaPooh...
不过它是只坚强的小乌龟
...but,you know,he's a tough little turtle.
你上次说我应该 不惜代价挽救婚姻
You know how you said to do whatever it takes to fix my marriage?
对，我叫你 答应艾蜜莉所有要求
Yeah,I told you to give Emily whatever she wants.
你建议不错 不过我必须告诉你她开的条件
And while that was good advice,you should know that what she wants...
什么？
Yes？
就是叫我永远不能再见你
is for me not to see you anymore.
太疯狂了，你才做不到
That's crazy! You can't do that.
你要怎么告诉她？
What are you going to tell her?
天啊，你已经答应了 对不对？
Oh,my God!You've already agreed to this.
我知道自己很恶劣
It's awful,I know.
我心情也很糟糕 但是这是挽救婚姻的唯一方法
But I have to do this if I want my marriage to work.
我很希望跟她合好 必须挽救这段婚姻
And I do. I have to make this marriage work. I have to.
好在我们在她抵达之前 还可以继续见面
But the good thing is,we can still see each other until she gets here.
我真幸运
Lucky me!
天啊，这真是好消息
Oh,my God! That is good news,Ross!
自从拉普过世之后 最大的好消息
That's the best news I've heard since LaPooh died!
你不知道我有多难过
You have no idea what a nightmare this has been.
我也很痛苦
This is so hard.
是吗？真的吗，罗斯？
Oh,yeah,really? Is it,Ross?
我可以为你减轻压力
-Let me make this easier for you.
你做什么？ 愤而出走
-What are you doing?Storming out.
瑞秋，这是你家
-It's your apartment.
你看我有多火大
Yeah? Well,that's how mad I am!
臭巧克力糖
Damn Rolos!
你回来了 嘿
You're back!
这次出差如何？
How was your conference?
糟透了，我跟…同事吵架 到回来前都没合好
It was terrible. I fought with my colleagues the entire time.
怎么还有？
Are you kidding with this?
也就是整个周末都泡汤？
So your weekend was a bust?
也不会，我看到 唐纳德·特朗普（知名房地产商）等电梯
No,I got to see Donald Trump waiting for an elevator.
他在泰姬陵有私人玻璃电梯
You know,at the Taj Mahal he has his own private glass elevator.
都由欧狄斯电梯公司生产
That's right. Made by Otis Elevators.
那家公司很少做玻璃电梯
And they don't usually do glass.
你脑袋里都装什么啊？
What kinds of stuff do you know?
嗨
Hi
你也回来了
You're back too.
对，钱德，可以出来一下吗？
Ya！Chandler,Could I talk to you for a second?
烹饪大会好玩吗？
-How was your chef thing?
糟透了
-lt was awful.
有些人根本不会欣赏美食
Some people don't appreciate good food.
你的食物可能看起来很美味
Maybe the food tasted good at first...
吃下去却害人上吐下泻
...but then made everybody vomit and have diarrhea.
钱德 莫妮卡
Chandler! - Monica
旅馆费用多少？ 我要付我那一半
How much was the room? I'll pay my half.
很好，300元
Fine. $300.
300元？
$300?
就想成每间25元
Just think of it as $25 per room.
你们鬼叫什么？
What are you guys woofing about?
钱德从我皮包偷了20元
Chandler stole a 20 from my purse!
不会吧？
No
因为莫妮卡先偷我的钱 我只是拿回来
I was only stealing it back,the one that she stole from me.
这人不但是小偷还说谎
Stealing and now lying.
现在回头想想，我老是没有20元 你皮夹里倒是很多
You know what? Now that I think about it...I constantly find myself without 20s,and you always have lots.
你们应该看看她当时的表情
You should've seen the look on her face.
我不希望瑞秋恨我 真不知道该怎么办
I don't want Rachel to hate me. I don't know what to do.
你要听我的建议吗？
-You want my advice?
请说
-Yes. Please.
你听了一定不高兴
-You won't like it.
没关系
-That's okay.
你决定结婚太匆促了
You got married too fast.
这算哪们子忠告？ 看吧
-That's not advice. -I told you.
我去洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom.
要有人叫我别见你们其中一个 我绝对办不到
If anyone asked me to give up any of you,I couldn't do it.
我也不行
Me neither.
或许我可以
Maybe I could do it.
我知道你们听说 罗斯跟我的事情了
I know you guys heard about me and Ross.
我已经烦了一整天 请你们别再提起了
But I've been obsessing about it and would love not to talk about it.
我不知道这算不算提起
I don't know if this falls under that category...
不过罗斯就在后面
...but Ross is right back there.
那才不是罗斯
-That's not Ross. -Not that guy.
不是那个，虽然很像
He does look like him,though.
罗斯去洗手间了
Ross is in the bathroom.
天啊，开始了，现在就这样
Oh,my God! It's happening. It's already started.
我就像阿吉
I'm Kip.
你才不是阿吉
Yeah,you're not Kip.
你知道阿吉是谁吗？
Do you even know who Kip is?
谁管他？你是瑞秋
Who cares? You're Rachel.
阿吉是谁？
Who's Kip?
我以前的室友 以前也跟大家很好
My old roommate. We all hung out together.
那个可怜人
Oh,that poor bastard.
看吧？你们跟我说过那件事
You told me the story.
他以前跟莫妮卡约会 分手后
He and Monica dated.When they broke up,
你们都答应继续跟他当朋友 结果呢？
you all promised you'd stay his friend.And what happened?
他从此遭到排挤
He got phased out.
我们才不会排挤你
-You won't be phased out.
一定会，罗斯一定可以留下来 因为他是你哥哥
-Of course I am.It won't happen to Ross. He's your brother,
他又是你大学室友
your college roommate.
阿吉也不该受到这样的待遇
Kip didn't even have to be Kip.
我们以前处理得很糟糕
We handled that all wrong.
况且那是很久以前的事情
It was a long time ago.
对啊，瑞秋 当时我跟你还没出现
And it was before you and me were around.
他们根本不知道自己在做什么
They didn't know what they were doing.
钱德还留着小胡子哩
Chandler had a mustache,for crying out loud.
迟早有人会离开这个小圈圈 我以前还以为走的是菲比
It was just a matter of time.I just always assumed Phoebe would be the one to go.
亲爱的，拜托，你住得远 又不是谁的亲戚
Honey，come on！You live far away,you're not related.
很快就会被淡忘
You lift right out.
宾先生
Hey,Mr. Bing.
你住的饭店打电话来
That hotel you stayed at called.
说在你房间捡到睫毛夹
Someone left an eyelash curler in your room.
是我的
Yes,that was mine.
我以为你遇上一个女孩 她忘了带走
I figured you met a girl and she left it.
这种说法的确比较合理
That would have made more sense.
我都快要不认识你了
I don't even feel like I know you anymore.
我只问你一次就好
All right,I'm just going to ask you this one time.
无论你怎么说，我都相信你
Whatever you say,I'll believe you.
你是不是去参加同性恋大会？
Were you or were you not...on a gay cruise?
菲比
Phoebe
我不该说大家会淡忘你
I'm sorry about the whole "lifting out" thing.
你得跟着我
You gotta come with me.
去哪里？ 跟着我就对了
-Where? -Wherever I go.
我们可以重组一个团体 毕竟我跟你才是最棒的
You and me,we'll start a new group. We're the best ones.
好吧，不过记得拉乔伊入伙
Okay,but try to get Joey too.
菲比，我可以跟瑞秋 私下谈谈吗？
Phoebe,do you mind if l speak to Rachel alone?
当然
Sure.
再见，罗斯
Bye,Ross.
永远不见了
Forever.
嗨
Hi
你来做什么？
What are you doing here?
这不是违反规定？
Isn't this against the rules?
我跟莫妮卡谈过
I talked to Monica.
是我做这个选择
Look,I'm the one who made the choice.
我害大家必须要改变
I'm the one who's making things change.
所以离开的应该是我
So I should be the one to,you know,step back.
罗斯… 真的没关系
No,no,it's okay. Really.
很多人只有在感恩节见到妹妹 同学会才见到大学室友
Plenty of people just see their sisters at Thanksgiving...their college roommates at reunions
在“汉堡王”才见到乔伊
...and Joey at Burger King.
这样你舒服一点了吗？
Is that better?
一点也没有
No,it's not better.
我还是见不到你
I still don't get to see you.
瑞秋，换做你会怎么办？
What would you do? If you were me,what would you do?
首先，我在婚礼上 就不会说错名字
Well，First,I'd have said the right name at my wedding.
竟然得走到这一步
I can't believe this.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我也知道
I know that too.
瑞秋，抱歉打扰
Hey,Rach?Sorry to interrupt,
菲比说我们要去哪里
but Phoebe said you want to talk to me about a trip?
嘿
Hey
嗨
Hi
我来拿…没事
I just came over to drop off...nothing.
上周末过得很糟
So that weekend kind of sucked.
没错
Yeah,it did.
那大概结束了
So I guess this is over?
什么？
What？
我说你跟我啦 反正迟早得结束
You know,you and me. I mean,it had to end sometime.
为什么？
Why exactly?
因为我们上周末吵架啊
Because of the weekend. We had a fight.
钱德，别傻了
Chandler,that's crazy.
如果你每次吵架就分手 交往大概不会超过…
If you always gave up after a fight...you'd never be with anyone longer than
明白了
Oh
所以我们还可以继续？
This isn't over?
你真可爱
You are so cute!
当然，我们只是吵架
No,no. It was a fight.
吵过之后就算了
You deal with it and you move on.
根本没什么好害怕
It's nothing to freak out about.
真的？太好了
Really? Okay,great!
欢迎加入成熟恋人行列
Welcome to an adult relationship.
我们算是男女朋友？
We're in a relationship?
恐怕是
I'm afraid so.
好吧
Okey
嘿
Hey
莫妮卡，听说你上周的会议看到唐纳德·特朗普
I heard you saw Donald Trump at your convention.
对，我看到他在等电梯
Saw him waiting for an elevator.
瑞秋，借我睫毛夹 我的不见了
Can I use your eyelash curler? I lost mine.
好啊，在厕所
It's in the bathroom.
乔伊，过来一下
Can I talk to you for a second?
没错…
Yes.Yes.
你？跟你？
You?And you?
对，但是你不能告诉别人 还没人知道
But you cannot tell anyone. No one knows.
怎么会？何时？
But how? When?
在伦敦发生的
-lt happened in London.
伦敦？
-ln London!
我们之所以没告诉大家 是不想你们大惊小怪
The reason we didn't tell anyone because we didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
这的确是大事
But it is a big deal!
我非告诉谁不可
I have to tell someone!
不行…你不能说
No…You can't.
求你了，我知道这很痛苦
Please. Now,I know this is hard.
没错，痛苦死了
lt is. It hurts.
拜托你，我们就是 不想面对大家质问
We just don't want to deal with telling everyone.
求求你保证不说
Please just promise you won't tell.
好吧
All right.
不可思议
Man,this is unbelievable!
这是件好事，可是…
I mean,it's great!But....
我知道，的确很棒
I know. It's great!
我可不想看到这一幕
I don't want to see that!
我们真是太蠢了
We're so stupid.
你知道他们在做什么吗？
Do you know what's going on in there?
他们想抢走乔伊
They're trying to take Joey!
网球界最有名的菲比 就叫做杀球菲比
"The most popular Phoebe in tennis is called the overhand Phoebe.
赢了就得跟对方击掌 说“嗨，菲比”
If you win,slap your opponent on the Phoebe and say,'Hi,Phoebe!'"
真有意思，很好玩
That's cute. We really all enjoyed it.
但是这不算
-But it doesn't count.
不算什么？
-For what?
这可不算疯狂猜谜
Just count in our heads as good Mad Libs.
我不想玩了 不好玩了
-I gotta go. -Fun's over.
等等，要遵守规则才有意思 也才有意义啊
Wait,if we follow the rules...it's still fun and it means something.
我要走了
I'm going to take off.
有规则才好 不守规则怎么会好玩
Guys,rules are good!Rules help control the fun.